BERTHA KUO

UX DESIGNER

Visit: berthakuo.com Phone: 707-386-5675 Email: berthakuo@gmail.com

PROFILE

Experienced user interface designer that uses a human-centered design approach to solve problems. Creates solutions that are useful and usable by building a deep understanding of the user and incorporating that knowledge throughout each stage of the design process. Guides project teams through ambiguity through iterative design and testing to produce well-defined wireframes. Motivated to make our everyday interactions with technology seamless.

UX SKILLS

- Personas
- Wireframes
- Usability Testing
- User Research
- Heuristic Evaluations
- Project Briefs
- OOUX

TOOLS

- Sketch
- Adobe XD
- Axure
- Balsamiq

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX Designer II

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, IS&T

August 2014 - May 2019

As a UX Designer, I've worked on products that support the MIT community including administrative applications, departmental dashboards, and learning management systems.

- Conducted upfront user research to define user workflows, needs and pain points.
- Planned and conducted in-person usability tests of web-based applications. Presented findings and recommendations to project team.
- Designed wireframes for administrative applications.
- Designed data visualizations for dashboards.

Human Factors Specialist

UL Wiklund R&D

January 2013 - January 2014

- Supported usability testing of home-use and hospital-based medical devices including exploratory testing of early UI concepts/prototypes and large-scale validation testing for FDA approval
- Performed root cause analysis and translated findings into design recommendations

Systems Engineer

Life Technologies

December 2009 - October 2010, March 2011 - March 2012

> Designed, wrote, executed and presented test plans for validation and verification of automated bead preparation system

Qualtrics

WEB DEV

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- GIT

- Supported field service engineers to diagnose and resolve customer issues
- Trained new employees and supervised their progress

EDUCATION

B.S., Biomedical Engineering University of California Davis 2002 - 2006